

VARJE KASS

Software Developer

PROFILE

I started studying programming in 2015 and have been working as a developer since 2017. Programming world is fascinating as it is in constant change.

In my free time, I enjoy dancing and volunteer at a mental health center and NGO Kohalugu.

I am looking forward to widening my expertise as software developer.

CONTACT

EMAIL:

varjekass@gmail.com

PHONE:

+372 59 03 96 97

WEBSITE:

www.varjekass.com

LINKEDIN:

www.linkedin.com/in/varje-kass

REFERENCE:

Carlos Bentes, STACC Tech Lead carlos.bentes@stacc.ee; +37257419986

EDUCATION

Tartu Vocational Education Centre

2016 - 2018

Specialty: junior software developer (web specialist)

Thesis: Web-application for creating and evaluating personalized

recommendations

University of Tartu

2012 - 2016

Specialty: Biology, BSc

Thesis: Protein Mgm101 and its deletion impact on the stability of

mitochondrial DNA

WORK EXPERIENCE

STACC OÜ – UI Developer

April 2017-present

Working with different projects for private and public sector.

During my worktime, I have gained experience with creating designs and mockups, doing front-end and back-end development, testing, data visualization and task management.

Main tools: Python, JavaScript, Git, Django, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, PostgreSQL, Moqups

Baltmi AS - Encoder

March 2016-April 2017

Encoding data for research on household consumption.

Main tools: MS Office, Internal database tool

University of Tartu – Microbiologist internship

October 2013-May 2016

Experiments in biochemistry laboratory with yeasts proteins. Main tools: MS Office, PCR, Autoclave, Gel Electrophoresis

SKILLS

Python	
JavaScript	
CSS	
HTML	
PostreSQL	
Git	